<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pyotek&#39;s Projects</title>
    <link>https://pyotek.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pyotek&#39;s Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 16:33:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pyotek.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PiceCold</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/news/picecold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 16:33:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/news/picecold/</guid>
      <description>Why do you need a cold wallet for your Bitcoins? Imagine the following scenario:
Your PC gets compromised. You do not notice it. You secured your wallet with a password which is sufficient? Does not matter, the attacker installed a keylogger. He only needs to sniff your password next time you do a transaction.
Because the attacker is friendly enough (and because this is a theoretic scenario), he only stole 1 BTC out of your wallet and left a note on your desktop:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Couch-Gaming Script</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/news/display-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 17:51:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/news/display-switch/</guid>
      <description>Intro Playing PC games from the couch on a bigger screen is fun.
But it requires additional steps, especially if the external bigger (TV) screen is not your primary display:
 Switch your display (this can be done by pressing WIN+P) Start Steam or another gaming platform (e.g. in Big Picture mode)   Hey, those are just 2 additional steps, so what&amp;rsquo;s the deal?
 Personally, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to wait until the PC is fully started to setup everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donations</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:50:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/donate/</guid>
      <description>Why donate? All of my projects are free to use.
Of course, it would be amazing if you want to donate something and therewith appreciate my work. Donations also motivate and show me that I am not doing completely useless stuff.
With your donation, you support me so that I am able to invest more in ideas, development, coffee and new hardware. How? Currently, only Bitcoin  donations are supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing PowHash</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/news/powhash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 22:13:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/news/powhash/</guid>
      <description>The idea File Hashing is the correct way to determine data integrity of your downloads and more. Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s practical to have built-in OS capabilities to hash files.
The PowerShell provides a nice and easy-to-use way to do that - the Get-FileHash Utility Cmdlet. That&amp;rsquo;s right: File-Hashing with MD5 and various SHA&amp;hellip; variants ready to use in Windows!
Tired of old batch scripts? The PowerShell does have some really nice and powerful features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mod a SNES Gamepad</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/news/snes-ctrl-mod/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 01:14:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/news/snes-ctrl-mod/</guid>
      <description>Ever wanted to make a SNES gamepad wireless? Read on!
Introduction This project description shows how I modified a SNES USB Gamepad/Controller to make it work wirelessly (frequency: 2.4 GHz) by combining it with a wireless keyboard.
I mostly used XodusTech&amp;rsquo;s site as a starting point. The site helped me with understanding how to marry the gamepad with the keyboard&amp;rsquo;s 2.4 GHz transmitter, so you probably want to visit it, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcode snippets for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/news/shortcodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 02:02:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/news/shortcodes/</guid>
      <description>Shortcodes help you with writing your content markdown files in Hugo. Instead of using raw HTML, they offer a more easy-to-use and easy-to-read syntax.
Save the shortcode in the &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/static/shortcodes/ directory of your website.
This page will possibly be updated to add more shortcodes.
Hyde-X tag Want to use tags (categories) when using the Hyde-X theme like this? Then this line is for you:
&amp;lt;a class=&amp;quot;label&amp;quot; href=&#39;{{ &amp;quot;/categories/&amp;quot; | absURL }}{{ .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/news/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:49:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/news/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hi and welcome! I created this page to provide an overview about my GitHub projects.
The sidebar shows the - yet unpopulated - categories (as of writing  Make &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; Mod and  Scripts).
It will be filled with more content, soon. I am going to migrate some existing projects to GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlight.js License (2016-08-07)</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/licenses/highlight-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 16:13:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/licenses/highlight-js/</guid>
      <description>Copyright &amp;copy; 2006, Ivan Sagalaev All rights reserved. Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:
* Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer. * Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyde License (2016-08-07)</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/licenses/hyde/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 16:13:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/licenses/hyde/</guid>
      <description>Released under MIT License Copyright &amp;copy; 2013 Mark Otto.
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyde-X License (2016-08-07)</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/licenses/hyde-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 16:13:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/licenses/hyde-x/</guid>
      <description>The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright &amp;copy; 2014 Andrei Mihu
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material Docs License (2016-08-07)</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/licenses/hugo-material-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 16:13:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/licenses/hugo-material-docs/</guid>
      <description>Copyright &amp;copy; 2016 Digitalcraftsman digitalcraftsman@protonmail.com
Copyright &amp;copy; 2016 Martin Donath martin.donath@squidfunk.com
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripts</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 13:17:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/scripts/</guid>
      <description>  ScriptsSnippet
Scripts and small pieces of code.
Links listed here are direct links to GitHub. To find related posts, click on the category tags (they look like this).
 PowerShell  PowHash - file hashing with progress and drag &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; drop Couch-Gaming Script - Switch display based on USB device  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make &#39;n&#39; Mod</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/make-n-mod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 16:15:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/make-n-mod/</guid>
      <description>Make &amp;#39;n&amp;#39; Mod
DIY stuff: Hardware modifications, 3D printing and more.
Hardware mods  Make a SNES Gamepad/Controller wireless  3D printing models &amp;hellip; to be continued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pyotek.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 16:13:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pyotek.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>General This GitHub page provides an overview of my projects. It is a simple, mobile-first page with the aim to load fast - especially on smartphones.
JavaScript This page&amp;rsquo;s basic functionality should work without enabled JavaScript. However, for eventual client-side syntax highlighting or embedded gists, it is recommended to turn it on. 
 Currently, JavaScript is disabled within your browser.
Donations Read about them here if you want to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>