<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pyotek&#39;s Projects</title><link>https://pyotek.co/</link><description>Recent content on Pyotek&#39;s Projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 03:06:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pyotek.co/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Development</title><link>https://pyotek.co/development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 13:17:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/development/</guid><description> DevWebAppScripts
Software, (Web-) Applications, Scripts and other related Software engineering work.
Links listed here are direct links to GitHub. To find related posts, click on the category tags above.
PowerShell PowHash - file hashing with progress and drag &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; drop Couch-Gaming Script - Switch display based on USB device</description></item><item><title>Make &#39;n&#39; Mod</title><link>https://pyotek.co/make-n-mod/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 16:15:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/make-n-mod/</guid><description>MakeModDIY
Open Source DIY projects, hardware modifications/customizations and more.
Hardware mods Make a SNES Gamepad/Controller wireless 🎮 3D printing models Come back here, soon!</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://pyotek.co/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 16:13:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/about/</guid><description>General This GitHub page provides an overview of Pyoteks work on current projects. It is a simple, AMP-compatible mobile-first HTML5 blog with the aim to load blazingly fast. 🚀
Every person should have the right to access our content in near-zero time. Have fun!
Donations Read more about them here if you want to.
Privacy Cookies This website does not use any cookies nor does it collect any Personally Identifiable Information (PII).</description></item><item><title>Pyotek Reboots</title><link>https://pyotek.co/p/pyotek-reboots/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 03:06:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/p/pyotek-reboots/</guid><description>What is this Pyotek, anyways? For now, it is a Tech-Blog that respects your privacy with a strong focus on Software and Hardware projects. On the other hand, it is also a GitHub organization/collective (yeah, currently a one-man show) that works on Open Source projects.
Follow Pyotek on its journey!
Oh hey, we have a fresh new Instagram account now, too - check it out! Technical This site is built via Hugo a fantastic static site generator that utilizes Go&amp;rsquo;s template mechanism and is therewith pretty fast.</description></item><item><title>Offline</title><link>https://pyotek.co/offline/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 16:13:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/offline/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;re offline. Sorry, we have not been able (pre-)cache this site. Come back when you&amp;rsquo;re online and we&amp;rsquo;re happy to meet again!
Congratulations, through no fault of the Enrichment Center, you have managed to trap yourself on this page.</description></item><item><title>PiceCold</title><link>https://pyotek.co/p/picecold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 16:33:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/p/picecold/</guid><description>Why do you need a cold wallet for your Bitcoins? Imagine the following scenario:
Your PC gets compromised. You do not notice it. You secured your wallet with a password which is sufficient? Does not matter, the attacker installed a keylogger. He only needs to sniff your password next time you do a transaction.
Because the attacker is friendly enough (and because this is a theoretic scenario), he only stole 1 BTC out of your wallet and left a note on your desktop:</description></item><item><title>Donations</title><link>https://pyotek.co/donate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:50:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/donate/</guid><description>Donate via &amp;nbsp; Donate ₿itcoin&amp;nbsp; Donate Ξther&amp;nbsp;
Exactly here, there should be a video. Your browser does not seem to display it correctly.
Donate via PayPal You will shortly be redirected to PayPal (after clicking the button). Otherwise use this static link. Donate via PayPal You will shortly be redirected to PayPal (after clicking the button). Otherwise use this static link.</description></item><item><title>Introducing PowHash</title><link>https://pyotek.co/p/powhash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 22:13:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/p/powhash/</guid><description>The idea File Hashing is the correct way to determine data integrity of your downloads and more. Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s practical to have built-in OS capabilities to hash files.
The PowerShell provides a nice and easy-to-use way to do that - the Get-FileHash Utility Cmdlet. That&amp;rsquo;s right: File-Hashing with MD5 and various SHA&amp;hellip; variants ready to use in Windows!
Tired of old batch scripts? The PowerShell does have some really nice and powerful features.</description></item><item><title>Mod a SNES Gamepad</title><link>https://pyotek.co/p/snes-ctrl-mod/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 01:14:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/p/snes-ctrl-mod/</guid><description>Ever wanted to make a SNES gamepad wireless? Read on!
Introduction This project description shows how I modified a SNES USB Gamepad/Controller to make it work wirelessly (frequency: 2.4 GHz) by combining it with a wireless keyboard.
I mostly used XodusTech&amp;rsquo;s site as a starting point. The site helped me with understanding how to marry the gamepad with the keyboard&amp;rsquo;s 2.4 GHz transmitter, so you probably want to visit it, too.</description></item><item><title>Hyde License (2016-08-07)</title><link>https://pyotek.co/licenses/hyde/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 16:13:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/licenses/hyde/</guid><description>Released under MIT License Copyright &amp;copy; 2013 Mark Otto.
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description></item><item><title>Hyde-X License (2016-08-07)</title><link>https://pyotek.co/licenses/hyde-x/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 16:13:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/licenses/hyde-x/</guid><description>The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright &amp;copy; 2014 Andrei Mihu
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://pyotek.co/bagdes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pyotek.co/bagdes/</guid><description>Donate via &amp;nbsp; Donate ₿itcoin&amp;nbsp; Donate Ξther&amp;nbsp;</description></item></channel></rss>